Guide to the History of Medicine Picture File, 1523-2002 and undated RL.00570
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
History of Medicine picture file
1523-2002 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00570
16 Linear Feet approximately 2400 items
Assembled by the staff of the Duke University Medical Library, the History of Medicine Picture File holds thousands of small and large images organized into series for individuals, places, and subjects related to the history of medicine and medical practice. The great majority portray notable physicians, scientists, naturalists, philosophers, and other individuals with important links to medicine. Places featured include hospitals and other institutions of medicine, and scenes in specific locations related to events in medical history. The subject categories cover many topics, with the largest groups including advertising, anatomy, caricatures, cartoons, pediatrics, physicians, and surgery. Predominant formats are engravings, lithographs, print materials (such as posters, clippings, and postcards), and many modern photographic reproductions of older works; there are also albumen photographs, negatives, slide reproductions, and other image formats found throughout the files. Forms part of the History of Medicine Collections at Duke University.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The History of Medicine picture file was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer from the Medical Center Library in 2011.
Historical Note
The History of Medicine Picture File was assembled as a reference and research resource by Duke University Medical Library staff over several decades and formed part of the History of Medicine Collections. The majority of the items were received as gifts and purchases from various individuals, many of whom were affiliated with Duke University and the School of Medicine; among the most frequent donors were the late Dr. Josiah Trent and Henry Schumann.
The Duke University History of Medicine Collections acquire, preserve, interpret, and make available for research and instruction, materials documenting the history of medicine, biomedical science, health and disease in the global context of the Western medical tradition.
Collection Overview
Assembled by the staff of the Duke University Medical Library, the History of Medicine Picture File offers thousands of images of individuals, places, and subjects dating from the 1500s to 2002, with the great majority portraying physicians, scientists, nurses, and other individuals related to the history or practice of medicine. Places featured include hospitals and other institutions of medicine, and scenes related to events in medical history. Subject categories include advertising, anatomy, books, caricature, childbirth, embryology, medical instruments, pediatrics, physicians, and surgery, among many others.
Most of the images measure in size under 10x12 inches, but there are approximately 500 larger pieces. The predominant formats are engravings, lithographs, cartoons, clippings from magazines and newspapers, and modern photographic prints, but there are also albumen photographs and other image formats found throughout the files. Items were acquired by the Duke Medical Library from various sources over many decades and functioned as a vertical file for library students and researchers.
The oversize items range in size from 11x15 to 23x30 inches, and offer a varied assemblage of portraits, caricatures, posters, broadsides, and reproductions of artwork, in black-and-white and in color. Items include portraits and scenes with notable physicians; illustrations of various medical practices, procedures, and instruments; anatomical views, some possibly as early as the 17th century; medical advertisements and promotional literature; depictions of events in medical history in Europe and North America; caricatures; 20th century illustrations for book covers; and many other topics.
Images and prints are often accompanied by reproduction negatives and slides created by Medical Center Library staff. Many of the images in this collection were also scanned by Medical Library staff and are available through the Medical Center Library & Archives Duke Medicine Digital Repository database. For more information, please contact the History of Medicine Curator at the Rubenstein Library.
Acquired as part of the History of Medicine Collections at Duke University.
Existence and Location of Copies note
Many images were scanned by Duke University Medical Library staff and can be found online by searching the Duke Medical Center Library & Archives image database.
Related Material
William H. Helfand Collection of Medical Prints and Posters, 1695-1991, bulk 1800-1899
Rubenstein Library, Duke University
Howard Kelly Collection of Florence Nightingale Prints and Photographs, circa 1840-1949 and undated
Rubenstein Library, Duke University
History of Medicine Print Materials Collection [contains related pictorial material]
Rubenstein Library, Duke University
Medicine -- History -- Pictorial works; Pediatrics -- History; Medicine -- History; Hospitals -- Pictorial works; Physicians -- Caricatures and cartoons; Advertising -- Medicine; Physicians -- Portraits; Physicians -- Pictorial works; Surgery -- History; Scientists -- Portraits; Surgery -- Pictorial works; Black-and-white photographs; Color photographs; Caricatures; Cartoons; Broadsides (notices); Slides (photographs); Scientific illustrations (images); Albumen prints; Technical illustrations (images); Engravings (prints); Lithographs; Etchings; Posters; Negatives (photographs); Pharmacology -- History; Pediatrics -- Pictorial works; Pharmacology -- Pictorial works; Medical colleges -- Pictorial works; Human anatomy -- Pictorial works; Human anatomy -- Early works to 1800; Human anatomy -- History; Human anatomy -- Models -- Early works to 1800; Anatomy, Artistic -- Pictorial works
- History of Medicine Picture File: People Series, approx. 1851 items
  Scope and Contents note
  Series contains images of significant anatomists, chemists, physicians, biologists, and other individuals in the field of medicine, arranged alphabetically by last name. Most depict 19th century men, primarily from European nations, particularly Germany, England, France, and Italy, and from North America, but there are also individuals active as early as the 15th century and as late as the 20th century. In many cases there are multiple images of the same individual in the folder.
  The predominant formats are engravings, lithographs, modern black-and-white photographs, and printed images (chiefly clippings on glossy paper), but there are other formats present such as albumen prints and negatives. Oftentimes the image is a modern photographic reproduction of an engraving, painting, sculpture, or other work. Images are also often accompanied by a slide or negative reproduction created as far back as the 1960s by Duke University Medical Center Library staff. Sizes range from small prints ranging from 2x3 to 10x12 inches, housed in manuscript boxes, to oversize items in flat boxes up to 23x30 inches. The sizes of the larger boxes are given in the container inventory.
  - Abbe, Ernst (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aescalupius, box size: 11.5x15 inches (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Abel, John Jacob (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abernethy, John (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Abraham, J.J. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Acland, Henry W. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Adami, John George, 1862-1926, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Addison, Thomas, 1793-1860 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Aesculapius [Asclepius] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Agassiz, Louis (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Agnew, David Hayes (Box 1, Folder 9)
    (Includes negatives)
  - Agricola, Georg Andreas, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Includes slide.
  - Agrippa, Heinrich Cornelius, 1486-1535 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Aito, Kenji (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Akenside, Mark (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Albert, Eduard (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Albinus, Bernardus Siegfried (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Albinus, Bernardus Siegried, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Aldrouandus, Ulysses (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Alexander, John (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Allen, Edgar van Nuys (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Allen, Willard Myron (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Alvarez, Walter C. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Anderson, Alexander (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Anderson, James (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Armstrong, John (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Aschoff, Ludwig (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Aselli, Gaspare, 1581-1626 (Asellius, Gaspar), 2 folders, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
    One small portrait and one enlargement.
  - Association of Military Surgeons (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Astruc, Joannes (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Atlee, Washington Lemuel (Box 1, Folder 28)
    (Includes negative)
  - Baas, Johann Hermann (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Babington, William, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Bacon, Sir Francis, box size: 20x24 inches (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Baer, Abraham Adolf (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Baer, Karl Ernst von, 1792-1876 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Baeyer, Adolph von (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Baglivi, Giorgio, 1668-1707 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Baillie, Matthew (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Baillie, Matthew, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Baillie, Matthew, box size: 18.5 x 24 inches (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Baillie, Matthew, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Baillou, Guillaume De (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Baity, F.H. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Ballantyne, John William (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Banks, Sir Joseph (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Banks, Sir Joseph, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Bantinq, Frederic Grant (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Bar (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Barclay, Robert Gutzlaff (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Barcroft, Joseph, 1872-1947 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Bardeleben, Adolf von (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Barker, Llewellys (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Bartelmez, George William (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Bartels, Max (Maximilian), 1843-1904 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Barthez, Antoine Charles Ernest (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Bartholin, Caspar (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Bartholin, Thomas (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Barton, Benjamin Smith (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Basch, Samuel S. von (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Battey, Robert, 1828-1895 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Batty, Robert, 1763-1849 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Baudelocque, Cesar-Auguste, 1795-1851 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Bauhin, Caspar (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Bautelwez, George William (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Bayle, Pierre (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Baylies, Guillaume (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Bayne-Jones, Stanhope (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Beattie, William (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Beaumont, William, 1785-1853 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Beck, Theodric Romeyn (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Beclard, Auguste (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Beddoes, Thomas, 1760-1808 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Behring, Emil Adolf von, 1852-1931 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Behring, Emil, box size: 23 x 30 inches (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Bell, Benjamin (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Bell, Charles (Sir), 1774-1842 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Bell, John (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Belon, Pierre (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Belt, Elmer (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Berger, Johannes [Hans] (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Bernard, Claude, 1813-1878 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Bernheim (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Bernoulli, Daniel, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Bert, Paul, 1833-1886 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Berthollet, Claude Louis (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Berzelius, Jöns Jakob (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Beverwyck, Johannes van, 1594-1647 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Bichat, Marie François Xavier, 1771-1802 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Bichat, Xavier, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Bidloo, Govert, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Bigelow, Henry Jacob, 1816-1890, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Billings, John Shaw, 1838-1913 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Billroth, Theodor (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Binz, Carl (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Black, Joseph, 1728-1799 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Black, William (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Blackwood, Henry, 1588-1634 (Blacvodaevs, Henricvs) (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Bland, Pascal Brooke (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Bland-Sutton, John (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Bland-Sutton, John, box size: 16x 20 inches (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Blane, Gilbert (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Blanton, Wyndham B. (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Bloodgood, Joseph Colt (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Blumenbach, Johann Friedrich (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Blundell, James (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Boerhaave, Hermann (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Boirrat (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Boivin, Veure Marie-Anne-Victoire (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Boldrey, Edwin B. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bollinger, Otto (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bonetus, Theophilus, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Bonus, Ephraim, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Boone, Alex W. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Boorde, Andrewe (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Borelli, Giovanni Alfonso (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bostock, John (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Boudewyns, Michael (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bouilland, Jean-Baptiste (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bowditch, Henry I. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bowditch, Henry Pickering, 1840-1911 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Boyer, Baron Alexis de (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Boyle, Robert, 1627-1691 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Boyle, Robert, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Boyle, Robert, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Boyle, Robert (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Bradley, W. N. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bragadino, Marco (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Brahe, Tycho [Tyge Ottesen Brahe] (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Briggs, William, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Bright, Richard (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Bram, Israel (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bright, Richard, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Brillat-Savarin, Jean Anthelme (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Brindeau, [Auguste?] (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Brocklesby, Richard (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Brodie, Benjamin Collins, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Brödel, Max, 1870-1941 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Broussais, F. J. V. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Brown, John, 1810-1882 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Brown, John, 1735-1788 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Brown, John Symonds (b. 1904) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Brown-Sequard, Charles Edward (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Browne, Edward (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Browne, Joannis (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Browne, Sir Thomas (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Buchan, William (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Budd, Richard (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Buhl, Ludwig (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Bulleyn, William (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Bunker, Chang and Eng (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Scope and Contents
    Color photograph of manikins or marionettes representing the Bunker conjoined twins, taken at a circus display.
  - Burke, William, 1792-1829 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    London resident hanged as murderer and seller of cadavers; accomplice was William Hare.
  - Burrows, Harold (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Cadwalader, Thomas (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Cadogan, Gulielmus, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Caius, John (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Calhoun, S. (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Calmette, Albert, 1863-1933 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Camerarius, Ludwig Joachim (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Camerarius, Ioachimus (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Camerer, Johann Friedrich Wilhelm (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Cameron, Sir Hector (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Camper, Pierre (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Cannon, Walter Bradford (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Cannon, Walter B., 1871-1945; box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Capivacceus, Hieronymus [Padavinius] (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Cardan, Hieronymus, 1501-76 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Carpi, Giacomo Berengario da, 1470-1550 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Carrel, Alexis (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Carson, Joseph (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Carstairs (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Casmir, Friederich (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Casserius, Julius (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Castiglioni, Arturo, 1942, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 2)
    With long handwritten Latin/English dedication to Henry Schumann from Castiglioni, on separate board. Photo is fragile - handle with care.
  - Castiglioni, Arturo, "Dinner on the occasion of the seventieth birthday anniversary of Dr. Arturo Castilglioni...Waldorf-Astoria, New York, N.Y.," panoramic black-and-white photograph of guests at tables, with typed guest list, April 12, 1944, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Cesalpino, Andrea (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Chacon, Dionisio Daza (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Chain, Ernst (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Chamberlen, Paul (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Chapman, Nathaniel (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Charcot, Jean-Martin (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Charcot, Jean-Martin, box size: 23 x 30 inches (Box 18, Folder 1)
    "Une leçon du Docteur Charcot a La Salpétrière," engraving of scene at clinic with labels naming other attending physicians. Includes slide.
  - Charleton, Walter (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Cheke, Sir John (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Cheselden, William (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Chevreul, Michel Eugène, 1786-1889 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Cheyne, George (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Chiron, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Chovet, Abraham (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Christian, Dr. Henry (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Christison, Robert (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Chrobak, Rudolf (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Circulatory Conference, November 1971 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    Accompanied by list of participants shown in photograph. Includes two Duke University physicians: Norman Ratliff and Donald Hackel.
  - Clark, Sir Andrew (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Clark, James (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Clark, John G. (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Clark, Samuel M. D., 1875-1925 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Clarke, Sir Charles Mansfield (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Cleghorn, Georgius (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Clendening, Logan (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Clendening, Logan, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Cloquet, Joseph H. (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Clowes, William (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Coates, Reynell (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Cochran, John (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Coffin, Nathaniel (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Cogan, Thomas (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Cohnheim, Julius Friedrich, 1839-1884 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Colden, Cadwalleder (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Cole, F. J. (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Cole, Harold Harrison (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Cole, William (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Coley, Henri (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Collinson, Peter (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Collip, James Bertram (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Cook, James W., box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Cooke, Jacobi (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Cooley, Thomas B. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Cooper, Sir Astley Paston (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cooper, Sir Astley Paston, box size: 23 x 30 inches (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Cooper, Sir Astley, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Cooper, Ernest (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cooper, George M. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Crona, Olive (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Corner, George Washington (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Corning, James Leonard, 2 items; box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Includes a full biography of Corning on a separate sheet. Brittle items: handle with care!
  - Corvisart, Jean Nicholas (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Corvisart, Lucien R. F. E. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Cosmas and Damian (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Coste, Jean François (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Cotugno, Domenico (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Couvelaire, Alexandre (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cowles, Edward (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Cowley, M. Abraham (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Cratevas, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Crawford, T. Hamilton, box size: 18.5 x 24 inches (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Crawford, T. Hamilton, box size: 20x24 inches (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Crawford, T. Hamilton (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Crede, Carl Sigmund Franz (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Crescentius, P. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Crew, Nehemiah (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Crile, George Washington (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Cruikshank, William C. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Cruikshank, William C., box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Crummer, Le Roy, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Cruveilhier, Jean Baptiste (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Cruveilhier, Jean, 1791-893, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Cullen, Thomas S., 1928, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Cullen, William, 1710-1790 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Cullen, William (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Culpeper, Nicholas (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Currie, James (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Currie, James, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Curtis, Arthur (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Curtis, William (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Cushing, Erastus (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Cushing, Harvey (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Cushny, Arthur, 1866-1926 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Cuvier, Georges, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Da Costa, John Chalmers, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Da Vinci, Leonardo, 1452-1519 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Dale, Henry (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Dalton, John (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Dandy, Walter Edward (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Darwin, Charles (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Darwin, Erasmus (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Darwin, Erasmus, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Davies, John A. V., box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Davis, Nathan Smith (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Davy, Humphrey (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - de la Pitis, Robin (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Deckers, Frederick (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Dee, John (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - De Gorter, Johannes, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Denman (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Denman, Thomas (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Denman, Thomas, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Desault, Pierre (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Descartes, René, 1596-1650 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Dettweiler, Peter (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Deventer, Henricus A. (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Deville, Henri Sainte-Claire, box size: 23 x 30 inches (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Engraving of scene from clinic with name labels for other attending physicians.
  - Devraigne, Louis-Jules (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Digby, Kenelm, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Dickens, Charles, box size: 20x24 inches (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Dickinson, Robert Latou (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Dimock, Susan (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Dimsdale, Baron Thomas (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Dioscorides (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Dioscorides, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Dock, George (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Dodonaeus, Rembertus (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Doisy, Edward Adelbert (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Donders, Franciscus Cornelius, 1818-1889 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Donders, Franz Cornelis (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Donovan, Dr. Edward (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Dorsey, John Syng (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Dowell, E. M. (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Downman, Hugh (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Drinker, Cecil Kent (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Dryander, Johannes (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Dryander, Jonas (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Dubois, Baron Antoine (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Dubois, Antoine, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Duchenne de Boulogne, Guillaume-Benjamin-Amand (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Duchesne, Joseph (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Duke University college-age men posed as a group in front of unidentified building, black-and-white photograph, 1950s, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 70)
    "Karl Bishopric, Jr." is stamped on the back. Bishopric was a graduate of Duke. Accompanied by photograph of what looks to be the same building, without people.
  - Dunant, Jean-Henri (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Duncan, Andrew (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Duncan, James Matthews (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Dupuytren, Guillaume (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Eckhard, Conrad (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Ehrlich, Paul (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Emmet, Thomas Addis (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Erasmus, Desiderius, 1467-1536 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Esquirol, Jean Etienne Dominique, 1772-1840 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Ether Day: "Old-time Boston doctors on 'Ether Day'," from Boston Globe, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 80)